Mss.B.H88
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to Edmé François Jomard, Undated; 4-1/4x4; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Friday. A.L.S. 2p. and add. In French. Inquires of a work of his on Egypt. Refers to Arago. Old Call Number: B H88.4 no.21
  - Letter to Edmé François Jomard, Undated; 5x3-3/4; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    A.L.S. 1p. and add. In French. Praises his work. Old Call Number: B H88.4 no.20
  - Letter to N. B. Judd, Undated; 9x5-1/2; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Monday night. A.L.S. 1p. In German. Date is unknown for the presentation of religious object to members of the royal family. Old Call Number: B H88.57
  - Letter to Monsieur Leo, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Saturday. A.L.S. 2p. and add. In French. Concerning the translations of Madame de D[uchesse?] into English and German. Old Call Number: B H88.77
  - Letter to Monsieur Leo, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
  - Letter to Matthew Fontaine Maury, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Photo. of L. 2p. In German. Copy. Concerning his work on hydrography. Refers to Gay-Lussac. Presented by Helmut de Terra, grantee, Nov. 1960. Old Call Number: B H88.39
  - Letter to Frau Geheimräthin Ernestine von Meusebach, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Friday night. Photostat of A.L.S. 1p. In German. Old Call Number: B H88.11 no.8
  - Letter to Joseph Barclay Pentland, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Samedi. A.L.S. 1p. In French. Concerning Lyell's geology. Old Call Number: B H88.111
  - Letter to Henry William Pickersgill, Undated; 8x5-1/2; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Saturday. A.L. in 3rd. P. 1p. In French. Wishes he could see him. Refers to Tracy and Lafayette. Old Call Number: B H88.47
  - Letter to François-Just-Marie Raynouard, Passy, Undated; 9x5-1/4; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Saturday. A.L.S. 1p. and add. In French. Wishes to visit him. Refers to Arago. Old Call Number: B H88.59 no. 6
  - Letter to Antoine Augustin Renouard, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Friday. Photostat of A.L.S. 1p. and add. In French. Concerning a publication. Old Call Number: B H88.11 no.14
  - Letter to [M. Souverain?], Undated; 5x3-3/4; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Dimanche [Sunday]. A.L.S. 4p. In French. Concerning his publication. Old Call Number: B H88.8
  - Letter to Baron de Stael, Undated; 5x4; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Paris, Monday. A.L.S. 3p. In French. Invitation to meet Mr. Wedington and others. Old Call Number: B H88.59 no.7
  - Letter to John Hurford Stone, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Monday. Photostat of A.L.S. 2p. and add. In French. Concerning a publication. Old Call Number: B H88.11 no.20
  - Letter to Henry Philip Tappan, Berlin, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Potsdam, Xerox of A.L.S. 1p. and add. In French. Wishes to talk with him. Considers the U.S. "comme une seconde Patrie," and mentions Jefferson, Madison, and Gallatin. Old Call Number: B H88.97. July 6
  - Letter to Henry Philip Tappan, Berlin, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Potsdam, Xerox of A.L.S. 1p. and add. In French. Wishes to talk with him. Considers the U.S. "comme une seconde Patrie," and mentions Jefferson, Madison and Gallatin. Old Call Number: B H88.97
  - Letter to Gustav Friedrich Waagen, Undated; 8-1/2x5; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    A.L.S. 1p. and add. In German. Old Call Number: B H88.15 no.8
  - Letter to David Bailie Warden, [Feb. 7?]; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Photo. of A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. In French. Concerning locations on the Spanish main. FOR REFERENCE USE ONLY. Old Call Number: B H88.36. [Feb. 7?]
  - Letter to David Bailie Warden, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Photo. of A.L.S. 1p. and add. In French. Asks for comparison of American with French and English items. FOR REFERENCE USE ONLY. Old Call Number: B H88.36 Feb. 8
  - Letter to David Bailie Warden, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Photo.of A.L.S. 1p. and add. In French. Asks for publication on Cuba. FOR REFERENCE USE ONLY. Old Call Number: B H88.36. [June 24]
  - Letter to David Bailie Warden, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Dimanche [Sunday]. Photo. of A.L.S. 1p. and add. In French. Recommends the son of a friend. FOR REFERENCE USE ONLY. Old Call Number: B H88.36
  - Letter to David Bailie Warden, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Dimanche [Sunday]. Photo. of A.L.S. 3p. and add. In French. Statistics for the U.S. FOR REFERENCE USE ONLY. Old Call Number: B H88.36
  - Letter to David Bailie Warden, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Dimanche [Sunday]. Photo. of A.L.S. 3p. In French. Asks questions about geology of the U.S FOR REFERENCE USE ONLY. Old Call Number: B H88.36
  - Letter to David Bailie Warden, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Lundi [Monday]. Photo. of A.L.S. 1p. In French. Asks question. For REFERENCE USE ONLY. Old Call Number: B H88.36
  - Letter to David Bailie Warden, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Mardi [Tuesday]. Photo. of A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. In French. Asks question about the U.S. FOR REFERENCE USE ONLY. Old Call Number: B H88.36
  - Letter to David Bailie Warden, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Mardi [Tuesday]. Photo.of A.L.S. 1p. In French. Thanks him for communication. FOR REFERENCE USE ONLY. Old Call Number: B H88.36
  - Letter to David Bailie Warden, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Mardi [Tuesday]. Photo. of A.L.S. 2p. and end. In French. Question about the U.S. FOR REFERENCE USE ONLY. Old Call Number: B H88.36
  - Letter to David Bailie Warden, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Mercridi [Wednesday]. Photo. of A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. In French. Glad he has shown Banks up. FOR REFERENCE USE ONLY. Old Call Number: B H88.36
  - Letter to David Bailie Warden, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Mercridi [Wednesday]. Photo.of A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. In French. Concerning the U.S. FOR REFERENCE USE ONLY. Old Call Number: B H88.36
  - Letter to David Bailie Warden, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Mercridi [Wednesday]. Photo. of A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. In French. Met Ticknor. Wishes to visit. FOR REFERENCE USE ONLY. Old Call Number:B H88.36
  - Letter to David Bailie Warden, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Jeudi [Thursday]. Photo.of A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. In French. Concerning a possible visit by Scott. FOR REFERENCE USE ONLY. Old Call Number: B H88.36
  - Letter to David Bailie Warden, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Jeudi [Thursday]. Photo.of A.L.S. 1p., end. In French. Business. FOR REFERENCE USE ONLY. Old Call Number: B H88.36
  - Letter to David Bailie Warden, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Jeudi [Thursday]. Photo. of A.L.S. 1p. and end. In French. Thanks for his communication. FOR REFERENCE USE ONLY. Old Call Number: B H88.36
  - Letter to David Bailie Warden, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Jeudi [Thursday]. Photo. of A.L.S. 1p., end. In French. Sends him a new letter and comments on what he has done. FOR REFERENCE USE ONLY. Old Call Number: B H88.36
  - Letter to David Bailie Warden, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Jeudi [Thursday]. Photo. of A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. In French. Works on travel. FOR REFERENCE USE ONLY. Old Call Number: B H88.36
  - Letter to David Bailie Warden, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Vendridi [Friday]. Photo.of A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. In French. Asks about the Embargo. FOR REFERENCE USE ONLY. Old Call Number: B H88.36
  - Letter to David Bailie Warden, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Vendridi [Friday]. Photo. of A.L.S. 1p., end. In French. Received a letter for him from the president of the U.S. FOR REFERENCE USE ONLY. Old Call Number: B H88.36
  - Letter to David Bailie Warden, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Vendridi [Friday]. Photo.of A.L.S. 1p. and add. In French. Refuses invitation. FOR REFERENCE USE ONLY. Old Call Number: B H88.36
  - Letter to David Bailie Warden, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Samedi [Saturday]. Photo. of A.L.S. 2p., end. In French. Friendly letter. FOR REFERENCE USE ONLY. Old Call Number: B H88.36
  - Letter to David Bailie Warden, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Samedi [Saturday]. Photo. of A.L.S. 1p. and add. In French. Asks question concerning Kingston. FOR REFERENCE USE ONLY. Old Call Number: B H88.36
  - Letter to David Bailie Warden, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Samedi [Saturday]. Photo. of A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. In French. Asks information about an American. FOR REFERRENCE USE ONLY. Old Call Number: B H88.36
  - Letter to David Bailie Warden, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Photo. of A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. In French. Thanks for his letter. FOR REFERENCE USE ONLY. Old Call Number: B H88.36
  - Letter to David Bailie Warden, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Photo. of A.L.S. 1p., end. In French. Thanks for his help. FOR REFERENCE USE ONLY. Old Call Number: B H88.36
  - Letter to David Bailie Warden, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Photo. of A.L.S. 3p. In French. Questions Concerning U.S.commerce. FOR REFERENCE USE ONLY. Old Call Number: B H88.36
  - Letter to David Bailie Warden, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Photo. of A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. In French. Concerning the author of two volumes. FOR REFERENCE USE ONLY. Old Call Number: B H88.36
  - Letter to David Bailie Warden, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Photo. of A.L.S. 1p., end. In French. Asks for aid in procuring a copy of a map of the U.S. FOR REFERENCE USE ONLY. Old Call Number: B H88.36
  - Letter to David Bailie Warden, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Samedi [Satruday]. Photo. of A.L.S. 1p. and add.,end. In French. Accepts inivtation. FOR REFERENCE USE ONLY. Old Call Number: B H88.36
  - Letter to Hermann Weiss, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    A.L.S. 1p. and add. In German. Old Call Number: B H88.90. Aug. 18
  - Letter to Johann Carl Zeune, Undated; 8-3/4x5-1/4; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Thursday. A.L.S. 2p. and add. In German. Cannot help him on Arabic facts. His work on geography of Asia and Europe. Old Call Number: B H88.50
  - Memorandum of names of plants, Undated; 3-1/4x6-1/2; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    A.D. 1p. In French. See letter from H. W. Rickett to de Terra, Feb. 6, 1958, in regular correspondence file. Old Call Number: B H88.28
  - Note on geological material, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    A.D. 1p., end. Old Call Number: B H88.83